<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dataroot xmlns:od="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:officedata" generated="2007-07-06T17:31:17">
<world_atlas>
<countryID>1</countryID>
<countryname>United States</countryname>
<flag href="file://images/us-flag.tif" />
<continent>North America</continent>
<map href="file://images/us-map.tif" />
<desc_hist>Britain&apos;s American colonies broke with the mother country in 1776 and were recognized as the new nation of the United States of America following the Treaty of Paris in 1783. During the 19th and 20th centuries, 37 new states were added to the original 13 as the nation expanded across the North American continent and acquired a number of overseas possessions. The two most traumatic experiences in the nation&apos;s history were the Civil War (1861-65) and the Great Depression of the 1930s. Buoyed by victories in World Wars I and II and the end of the Cold War in 1991, the US remains the world&apos;s most powerful nation state. The economy is marked by steady growth, low unemployment and inflation, and rapid advances in technology.</desc_hist>
<area>9,631,418</area>
<desc_geo>World&apos;s third-largest country by size (after Russia and Canada) and by population (after China and India); Mt. McKinley is highest point in North America and Death Valley the lowest point on the continent</desc_geo>
<population>295,734,134</population>
<desc_culture>White 81.7%, black 12.9%, Asian 4.2%, Amerindian and Alaska native 1%, native Hawaiian and other Pacific islander 0.2% (2003 est.) 
note: a separate listing for Hispanic is not included because the US Census Bureau considers Hispanic to mean a person of Latin American descent (including persons of Cuban, Mexican, or Puerto Rican origin) living in the US who may be of any race or ethnic group (white, black, Asian, etc.)</desc_culture>
<language1>English</language1>
<language2>Spanish</language2>
<language3>Indo-European</language3>
</world_atlas>
<world_atlas>
<countryID>2</countryID>
<countryname>China</countryname>
<flag href="file://images/ch-flag.tif" />
<continent>Asia</continent>
<map href="file://images/chmap.tif" />
<desc_hist>For centuries China stood as a leading civilization, outpacing the rest of the world in the arts and sciences, but in the 19th and early 20th centuries, the country was beset by civil unrest, major famines, military defeats, and foreign occupation. After World War II, the Communists under MAO Zedong established an autocratic socialist system that, while ensuring China&apos;s sovereignty, imposed strict controls over everyday life and cost the lives of tens of millions of people. After 1978, his successor DENG Xiaoping and other leaders focused on market-oriented economic development and by 2000 output had quadrupled. For much of the population, living standards have improved dramatically and the room for personal choice has expanded, yet political controls remain tight.</desc_hist>
<area>9,596,960</area>
<desc_geo>World&apos;s fourth largest country (after Russia, Canada, and US); Mount Everest on the border with Nepal is the world&apos;s tallest peak</desc_geo>
<population>1,306,313,812</population>
<desc_culture>Han Chinese 91.9%, Zhuang, Uygur, Hui, Yi, Tibetan, Miao, Manchu, Mongol, Buyi, Korean, and other nationalities 8.1%</desc_culture>
<language1>Mandarin</language1>
<language2>Cantonese</language2>
<language3>Shanghaiese</language3>
</world_atlas>
<world_atlas>
<countryID>3</countryID>
<countryname>France</countryname>
<flag href="file://images/fr-flag.tif" />
<continent>Europe</continent>
<map href="file://images/fr-map.tif" />
<desc_hist>Although ultimately a victor in World Wars I and II, France suffered extensive losses in its empire, wealth, manpower, and rank as a dominant nation-state. Nevertheless, France today is one of the most modern countries in the world and is a leader among European nations. Since 1958, it has constructed a presidential democracy resistant to the instabilities experienced in earlier parliamentary democracies. In recent years, its reconciliation and cooperation with Germany have proved central to the economic integration of Europe, including the introduction of a common exchange currency, the euro, in January 1999. At present, France is at the forefront of efforts to develop the EU&apos;s military capabilities to supplement progress toward an EU foreign policy.</desc_hist>
<area>547,030</area>
<desc_geo>Largest West European nation</desc_geo>
<population>60,656,178</population>
<desc_culture>Celtic and Latin with Teutonic, Slavic, North African, Indochinese, Basque minorities</desc_culture>
<language1>French</language1>
</world_atlas>
<world_atlas>
<countryID>4</countryID>
<countryname>United Kingdom</countryname>
<flag href="file://images/uk-flag.tif" />
<continent>Europe</continent>
<map href="file://images/uk-map.tif" />
<desc_hist>Great Britain, the dominant industrial and maritime power of the 19th century, played a leading role in developing parliamentary democracy and in advancing literature and science. At its zenith, the British Empire stretched over one-fourth of the earth&apos;s surface. The first half of the 20th century saw the UK&apos;s strength seriously depleted in two World Wars. The second half witnessed the dismantling of the Empire and the UK rebuilding itself into a modern and prosperous European nation. As one of five permanent members of the UN Security Council, a founding member of NATO, and of the Commonwealth, the UK pursues a global approach to foreign policy; it currently is weighing the degree of its integration with continental Europe. A member of the EU, it chose to remain outside the Economic and Monetary Union for the time being. Constitutional reform is also a significant issue in the UK. The Scottish Parliament, the National Assembly for Wales, and the Northern Ireland Assembly were established in 1999, but the latter is suspended due to bickering over the peace process.</desc_hist>
<area>244,820</area>
<desc_geo>Lies near vital North Atlantic sea lanes; only 35 km from France and now linked by tunnel under the English Channel; because of heavily indented coastline, no location is more than 125 km from tidal waters</desc_geo>
<population>60,441,457</population>
<desc_culture>White (English 83.6%, Scottish 8.6%, Welsh 4.9%, Northern Irish 2.9%) 92.1%, black 2%, Indian 1.8%, Pakistani 1.3%, mixed 1.2%, other 1.6% (2001 census)</desc_culture>
<language1>English</language1>
<language2>Welsh</language2>
<language3>Scottish</language3>
</world_atlas>
<world_atlas>
<countryID>5</countryID>
<countryname>Mexico</countryname>
<flag href="file://images/mex-flag.tif" />
<continent>Central America</continent>
<map href="file://images/mex-map.tif" />
<desc_hist>The site of advanced Amerindian civilizations, Mexico came under Spanish rule for three centuries before achieving independence early in the 19th century. A devaluation of the peso in late 1994 threw Mexico into economic turmoil, triggering the worst recession in over half a century. The nation continues to make an impressive recovery. Ongoing economic and social concerns include low real wages, underemployment for a large segment of the population, inequitable income distribution, and few advancement opportunities for the largely Amerindian population in the impoverished southern states. Elections held in July 2000 marked the first time since the 1910 Mexican Revolution that the opposition defeated the party in government, the Institutional Revolutionary Party (PRI). Vicente FOX of the National Action Party (PAN) was sworn in on 1 December 2000 as the first chief executive elected in free and fair elections.</desc_hist>
<area>1,972,550</area>
<desc_geo>Strategic location on southern border of US; corn (maize), one of the world&apos;s major grain crops, is thought to have originated in Mexico</desc_geo>
<population>106,202,903</population>
<desc_culture>Mestizo (Amerindian-Spanish) 60%, Amerindian or predominantly Amerindian 30%, white 9%, other 1%</desc_culture>
<language1>Spanish</language1>
<language2>Mayan</language2>
<language3>Nahuatl</language3>
</world_atlas>
<world_atlas>
<countryID>6</countryID>
<countryname>Italy</countryname>
<flag href="file://images/it-flag.tif" />
<continent>Europe</continent>
<map href="file://images/it-map.tif" />
<desc_hist>Italy became a nation-state in 1861 when the city-states of the peninsula, along with Sardinia and Sicily, were united under King Victor EMMANUEL II. An era of parliamentary government came to a close in the early 1920s when Benito MUSSOLINI established a Fascist dictatorship. His disastrous alliance with Nazi Germany led to Italy&apos;s defeat in World War II. A democratic republic replaced the monarchy in 1946 and economic revival followed. Italy was a charter member of NATO and the European Economic Community (EEC). It has been at the forefront of European economic and political unification, joining the Economic and Monetary Union in 1999. Persistent problems include illegal immigration, organized crime, corruption, high unemployment, sluggish economic growth, and the low incomes and technical standards of southern Italy compared with the prosperous north.</desc_hist>
<area>301,230</area>
<desc_geo>Strategic location dominating central Mediterranean as well as southern sea and air approaches to Western Europe</desc_geo>
<population>58,103,033</population>
<desc_culture>Italian (includes small clusters of German-, French-, and Slovene-Italians in the north and Albanian-Italians and Greek-Italians in the south)</desc_culture>
<language1>Italian</language1>
<language2>German</language2>
<language3>French</language3>
</world_atlas>
<world_atlas>
<countryID>7</countryID>
<countryname>Japan</countryname>
<flag href="file://images/jp-flag.tif" />
<continent>Asia</continent>
<map href="file://images/jp-map.tif" />
<desc_hist>In 1603, a Tokugawa shogunate (military dictatorship) ushered in a long period of isolation from foreign influence in order to secure its power. For 250 years this policy enabled Japan to enjoy stability and a flowering of its indigenous culture. Following the Treaty of Kanagawa with the United States in 1854, Japan opened its ports and began to intensively modernize and industrialize. During the late 19th and early 20th centuries, Japan became a regional power that was able to defeat the forces of both China and Russia. It occupied Korea, Formosa (Taiwan), and southern Sakhalin Island. In 1933 Japan occupied Manchuria and in 1937 it launched a full-scale invasion of China. Japan attacked US forces in 1941 - triggering America&apos;s entry into World War II - and soon occupied much of East and Southeast Asia. After its defeat in World War II, Japan recovered to become an economic power and a staunch ally of the US. While the emperor retains his throne as a symbol of national unity, actual power rests in networks of powerful politicians, bureaucrats, and business executives. The economy experienced a major slowdown starting in the 1990s following three decades of unprecedented growth, but Japan still remains a major economic power, both in Asia and globally. In 2005, Japan began a two-year term as a non-permanent member of the UN Security Council.</desc_hist>
<area>377,835</area>
<desc_geo>Strategic location in northeast Asia</desc_geo>
<population>127,417,244</population>
<desc_culture>Japanese 99%, others 1% (Korean 511,262, Chinese 244,241, Brazilian 182,232, Filipino 89,851, other 237,914) 
note: up to 230,000 Brazilians of Japanese origin migrated to Japan in the 1990s to work in industries; some have returned to Brazil (2004)</desc_culture>
<language1>Japanese</language1>
</world_atlas>
<world_atlas>
<countryID>8</countryID>
<countryname>Canada</countryname>
<flag href="file://images/can-flag.tif" />
<continent>North America</continent>
<map href="file://images/can-map.tif" />
<desc_hist>A land of vast distances and rich natural resources, Canada became a self-governing dominion in 1867 while retaining ties to the British crown. Economically and technologically the nation has developed in parallel with the US, its neighbor to the south across an unfortified border. Canada&apos;s paramount political problem is meeting public demands for quality improvements in health care and education services after a decade of budget cuts. The issue of reconciling Quebec&apos;s francophone heritage with the majority anglophone Canadian population has moved to the back burner in recent years; support for separatism abated after the Quebec government&apos;s referendum on independence failed to pass in October of 1995.</desc_hist>
<area>9,984,670</area>
<desc_geo>Second-largest country in world (after Russia); strategic location between Russia and US via north polar route; approximately 90% of the population is concentrated within 160 km of the US border</desc_geo>
<population>32,805,041</population>
<desc_culture>British Isles origin 28%, French origin 23%, other European 15%, Amerindian 2%, other, mostly Asian, African, Arab 6%, mixed background 26%</desc_culture>
<language1>English</language1>
<language2>French</language2>
</world_atlas>
<world_atlas>
<countryID>9</countryID>
<countryname>Argentina</countryname>
<flag href="file://images/arg-flag.tif" />
<continent>South America</continent>
<map href="file://images/arg-map.tif" />
<desc_hist>Following independence from Spain in 1816, Argentina experienced periods of internal political conflict between conservatives and liberals and between civilian and military factions. After World War II, a long period of Peronist authoritarian rule and interference in subsequent governments was followed by a military junta that took power in 1976. Democracy returned in 1983, and numerous elections since then have underscored Argentina&apos;s progress in democratic consolidation.</desc_hist>
<area>2,766,890</area>
<desc_geo>Second-largest country in South America (after Brazil); strategic location relative to sea lanes between the South Atlantic and the South Pacific Oceans (Strait of Magellan, Beagle Channel, Drake Passage); Cerro Aconcagua is South America&apos;s tallest mountain, while Laguna del Carbon is the lowest point in the Western Hemisphere</desc_geo>
<population>39,537,943</population>
<desc_culture>White (mostly Spanish and Italian) 97%, mestizo (mixed white and Amerindian ancestry), Amerindian, or other non-white groups 3%</desc_culture>
<language1>Spanish</language1>
<language2>English</language2>
<language3>Italian</language3>
</world_atlas>
<world_atlas>
<countryID>10</countryID>
<countryname>Australia</countryname>
<flag href="file://images/aus-flag.tif" />
<continent>Oceania</continent>
<map href="file://images/aus-map.tif" />
<desc_hist>Aboriginal settlers arrived on the continent from Southeast Asia about 40,000 years before the first Europeans began exploration in the 17th century. No formal territorial claims were made until 1770, when Capt. James COOK took possession in the name of Great Britain. Six colonies were created in the late 18th and 19th centuries; they federated and became the Commonwealth of Australia in 1901. The new country took advantage of its natural resources to rapidly develop its agricultural and manufacturing industries and to make a major contribution to the British effort in World Wars I and II. In recent decades, Australia has transformed itself into an internationally competitive, advanced market economy. It boasted one of the OECD&apos;s fastest growing economies during the 1990&apos;s, a performance due in large part to economic reforms adopted in the 1980&apos;s. Long-term concerns include pollution, particularly depletion of the ozone layer, and management and conservation of coastal areas, especially the Great Barrier Reef.</desc_hist>
<area>7,686,850</area>
<desc_geo>World&apos;s smallest continent but sixth-largest country; population concentrated along the eastern and southeastern coasts; the invigorating tropical sea breeze known as the &quot;Fremantle Doctor&quot; affects the city of Perth on the west coast, and is one of the most consistent winds in the world</desc_geo>
<population>20,090,437</population>
<desc_culture>Caucasian 92%, Asian 7%, aboriginal and other 1%</desc_culture>
<language1>English</language1>
<language2>Chinese</language2>
<language3>Italian</language3>
</world_atlas>
</dataroot>
