<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<Root>
  <Cookbook>Krause Family Recipes

<Section>
<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Appetizers/Beverages</Sectionhead>
<Title>Clam Dip</Title>
<Ingredients>1 6-oz. can minced clams, with juice
1 8-oz. package cream cheese - softened
1/2 TBSP chopped onion
1/2 tsp Worcestershire sauce
1 TBSP sour cream
1 TBSP clam juice
generous dash garlic powder
Yields 1 cup</Ingredients>
<Directions>Combine all ingredients in a medium-sized bowl. Stir until all ingredients are completely blended. Serve immediately. Refrigerate any leftovers.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Appetizers/Beverages</Sectionhead>
<Title>Classic Cooked Eggnog</Title>
<Ingredients>6 eggs
1/4 cup sugar
1/4 tsp salt - optional
1 quart milk, divided - total 4 cups
1 tsp vanilla</Ingredients>
<Directions>Beat together eggs, sugar and salt in large saucepan.
Stir in 2 cups of the milk. Cook slowly over low hear till mixture is thick enough to coat metal spoon - about 160 . Remove from heat. Stir in remaining 2 cups of milk and vanilla. Cover and refrigerate until thoroughly chilled - several hours or overnight.
Sprinkle with nutmeg or whipped cream with crushed peppermint. Makes 12 1/2 cup servings.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Appetizers/Beverages</Sectionhead>
<Title>Fresh Cooked Shrimp</Title>
<Ingredients>2 TBSP vinegar
2 bay leaves
1 tsp mixed pickling spices
2 stalks celery, cut - can use leaves too
2 lbs. fresh/frozen shrimp in shells</Ingredients>
<Directions>Combine 6 cups water, 2 TBSP salt, vinegar, bay leaves, pickling spices and celery. Bring to boil. Add shrimp either in shells, or peeled and cleaned. Heat to boiling, then lower heat and simmer gently until shrimp turns pink - about 1-3 minutes. If cooked in shell, peel and clean. Can store in refrigerator for 2-3 days.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Appetizers/Beverages</Sectionhead>
<Title>Heidel House Cocktail Meatballs</Title>
<Ingredients>1 lb. hamburger
1 6-oz. can carnation evaporated milk
1 package dry onion soup mix
1 1/2 TBSP Worcestershire sauce</Ingredients>
<Subtitle>Sauce:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>1/3 cup brown sugar
1 cup catsup
1 1/2 tsp Worcestershire sauce</Ingredients>
<Directions>Add top four ingredients. Form into 1 inch balls. Brown in a skillet, remove and drain.
Mix sauce and bring to a boil. Pour over drained meatballs.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Appetizers/Beverages</Sectionhead>
<Title>Hidden Valley Oyster Crackers</Title>
<Ingredients>1 package 10 oz. Hidden Valley Original Ranch Salad Dressing Mix
1/2 tsp dill weed
1/2 cup salad oil
5 cups (11 oz.) plain oyster crackers
optional - 1/4 tsp lemon pepper
1/4 tsp garlic powder</Ingredients>
<Directions>Combine Hidden Valley Ranch Salad Dressing mix with dill weed and oil. Pour over crackers, stir to coat. Place in warm oven (275  F) for 15-20 minutes or microwave 60% power for 20 minutes. Stir gently halfway through baking.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Appetizers/Beverages</Sectionhead>
<Title>Maryland Crab Cakes</Title>
<Ingredients>1 egg well beaten
2 1/2 TBSP mayonnaise
1 1/2 tsp Worcestershire sauce
2 tsp lemon juice
dash Tabasco sauce, salt and pepper
5 crackers, crushed in a baggie
2 cups jumbo lump crabmeat (make sure it doesn’t smell)</Ingredients>
<Directions>Form into cakes and cook in nonstick pan with peanut oil or clarified butter.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Appetizers/Beverages</Sectionhead>
<Title>Tabouleh</Title>
<Ingredients>1 cup fine grain bulgur wheat
2 large bunches of parsley
1 small red bell pepper, cored, seeded, and cut into large chunks
2 stalks celery, cut into large pieces
2 bunches of scallions, cut into large pieces
2 TBSP coarsely chopped fresh mint leaves or 1 tsp dried mint
1/4 cup olive oil (extra virgin preferable)
1/4 cup lemon juice
1/4 tsp ground allspice
1/4 tsp ground cinnamon
1 tsp salt
1/4 tsp freshly ground black pepper
4 medium tomatoes, cut into 1/4” dice</Ingredients>
<Directions>Soak the bulgur wheat in 2 cups cold water for 15 minutes. Squeeze dry. Pick the parsley leaves from the large stems. Wash at least twice and drain very well. Mix the parsley, bell pepper, celery, scallions, and mint together, and place in a food processor with a metal blade. Pulse-whip until fine and place in a large mixing bowl. In a separate bowl mix the olive oil, lemon juice, spices and salt and pepper, and stir with fork or whisk until smooth.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Appetizers/Beverages</Sectionhead>
<Title>Texas Cavier</Title>
<Ingredients>Chick peas
Black beans
Chopped tomatoes
Chopped green chilies
Black olives
Chopped green peppers
Corn
Green onions</Ingredients>
<Directions>Put all in bowl. Add 4 TBSP lime juice and 2 TBSP olive oil. May add Tabasco sauce if desired. Makes lots of dip to use with tortilla chips.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Appetizers/Beverages</Sectionhead>
<Title>Tom and Jerry Mix</Title>
<Ingredients>Tom &amp; Jerry Mix
2 egg whites
1 shot of Brandy
Rum
1 cup Hot Water
Nutmeg
1/3 tsp Cream of Tartar
2 egg yolks
1/2 cup sugar</Ingredients>
<Directions>Beat egg whites until very stiff
Add Cream of Tartar, egg yolks, continue beating. Add sugar and FREEZE
Add T&amp;J mix to very hot water. Add 1 shot of brandy and 1-2 tsp rum. Top with nutmeg and serve.</Directions>

</Recipe>
</Section>

<Section>
<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>Artichoke Bread</Title>
<Ingredients>White frozen bread (1 loaf)
Artichoke hearts (oil packed)
Basil
Oregano
Garlic
Parmesan cheese </Ingredients>
<Directions>Roll out thawed dough, spread artichokes and herbs (use amounts to taste) across dough
Roll dough into swirl, pinch the seams.
Make a circle on cookie sheet, spread olive oil on top. Cover with moist cloth, let rise 30 minutes.
Bake at 375  for 15 minutes
Sprinkle Parmesan cheese on top, bake 10-15 minutes more. Finished when golden brown.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>Banana Nut French Toast</Title>
<Directions>Batter – whisk together eggs and milk, cream or buttermilk with vanilla or any other flavoring. Batter side of bread and fry in cast iron skillet. Spread a mixture of cut up bananas, brown sugar, and walnuts. Put mixture onto bread to make a sandwich. Fry outsides. Warm remaining banana walnut brown sugar. Put over French toast. </Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>Cinnamon-walnut Pull Apart Loaves</Title>
<Ingredients>6 1/2 cups flour
6 TBSP sugar
1 1/2 tsp salt
2 packages dry yeast
1 cup milk
3/4 cup water
1/3 cup margarine
3 eggs - room temperature
1/2 cup sugar
1/2 cup walnuts, finely chopped
2 tsp cinnamon or pumpkin pie spice
¼ cup margarine, melted</Ingredients>
<Directions>In bowl, mix 2 cups flour, 6 TBSP sugar, salt and yeast. Heat milk and 1/3 cup margarine to 120-130 . Margarine need not be melted. Add to dry ingredients. Beat with a mixer on medium speed for 2 minutes. Add 2 eggs and 1/2 cup flour. Beat on high for 2 minutes. Stir in remaining flour to make stiff dough. Knead 8-10 minutes. Set in greased bowl - grease top. Cover, let rise till doubled ~ 1 hour.
Combine 1/2 cup sugar, walnuts, and cinnamon. 
Punch the dough down. Divide in half. Roll each to 14x8 inch rectangle. Brush with melted margarine. Sprinkle each with 1/2 of nut mixture. Cut into 8x3 1/2 inch strips. Stack strips, cut into 3 1/2x2 inch pieces. Place on edge in a row in 2 greased 9x5x3 inch loaf pans. Cover, let rise till doubled. Bake at 375  for 25-30 minutes. Cool. Glaze with powdered sugar and water. Drizzle over top.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>Cranberry Nut Bread</Title>
<Ingredients>2 cups flour
1/2 tsp salt
1 1/2 tsp baking powder
1/2 tsp baking soda
1 cup sugar
1 beaten egg
2 TBSP melted shortening
1/2 cup plus 2 TBSP orange juice
1/2 cup chopped nuts
2 cups cut up cranberries</Ingredients>
<Directions>Combine dry ingredients. Mix well. In a separate bowl, combine rest of the ingredients. Add to the dry ingredients. Mix just until blended. Bake at 325  for 1 hour and 10 minutes.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>French Toast Casserole</Title>
<Ingredients>2 cups skim milk
3 whole eggs, lightly beaten
12 slices wheat or whole grain bread cut into halves
2 TBSP margarine, melted – divided
1 cup powdered sugar – divided
2 cups fresh raspberries – divided. May use frozen if not in season or other fresh fruit
1 tsp pumpkin pie spice or cinnamon</Ingredients>
<Directions>Preheat oven to 400 degrees. Lightly coat 9” square glass baking dish with vegetable oil spray. 
In small bowl, combine milk and eggs, lightly beat with fork until blended. Dip bread halves into mixture to coat well. Layer 1/3 of slices in bottom of baking dish. 
Lightly drizzle 1/3 of margarine over bread. Sprinkle 2 ½ TBSP sugar on top. Cover with ½ of the raspberries. Repeat another layer of bread – pattern differently from bottom layer. Top with 1/3 of the margarine 2 ½ TBSP sugar and remaining fruit. Cover with remaining bread, margarine sugar, and pumpkin pie spice.
Cover and bake 25 minutes. Uncover and bake additional 10-15 minutes. Makes 6-8 servings.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>Krause Pizza Dough</Title>
<Ingredients>1 package dry yeast
1 cup warm water
1 tsp sugar
1 1/2 tsp salt
2 TBSP olive oil
3 1/2 cups flour </Ingredients>
<Directions>Mix yeast and warm water. Stir well. Add sugar, salt, olive oil and 2 cups flour. Place on board/counter and knead in remaining 1 1/2 cups flour. Cover in large bowl. Place in a warm spot. Let double in size. Punch down and use. You can put on baking sheet. Prick with fork and bake 10 min. at 350 . Add toppings. Bake at 425  for 10-12 minutes.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>Lemon Muffins</Title>
<Ingredients>Vegetable oil cooking spray
1 3/4 cups all-purpose flour
3/4 cup sugar
1 tsp baking soda
1/4 tsp salt
1 cup lowfat or nonfat lemon, vanilla or plain yogurt
1 large egg
3 TBSP butter or margarine, melted and cooled
1 TBSP fresh lemon juice
1 TBSP finely grated lemon zest
1/4 tsp pure lemon extract (optional)</Ingredients>
<Directions>Heat oven to 350 . Spray 12 standard-sized muffin cups with vegetable oil cooking spray. 
Whisk together flour, sugar, baking soda and salt in a small bowl. Whisk together yogurt, egg, butter, lemon juice, lemon zest and lemon extract in a large mixing bowl. Add dry ingredients to yogurt mixture and stir with a rubber spatula just until blended; don’t over mix. Evenly divide batter among muffin cups, using about 1/4 cup per muffin. Bake for 20 to 22 minutes, or until the edges are golden brown. Remove muffins from tin immediately. Allow to cool slightly on a rack, but they are best served warm.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>Milk Toast</Title>
<Ingredients>3 slices of bread (better if you use sourdough or buttermilk) </Ingredients>
<Directions>cut in 1” cubes
cover with milk and 4 TBSP honey
heat in microwave for 2 minutes</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>Ponczkas</Title>
<Ingredients>2 cups milk
1 cup margarine
1 cup sugar
2 tsp salt
1/2 cup water
2 oz. yeast crumbled or 3 packages dry yeast
1 tsp sugar
6 eggs
1 tsp vanilla
8 cups flour</Ingredients>
<Directions>Scald 2 cups milk. Add margarine and wait till it melts. Then add 1 cup sugar and salt and cool until lukewarm. In 1/2 cup water add the yeast and 1 tsp. sugar. Wait until it rises and becomes bubbly and light - about 20 minutes. In a large bowl beat the 6 eggs. Add the cooled milk mixture, the yeast and vanilla. Add 8 cups of flour gradually, mixing well with a spoon. Refrigerate covered overnight or at least 4 hours.
Roll out dough on floured surface, about 1/2 inch thick. Cut in circles with a glass - about fruit juice size. May add prunes now and fold dough over to cover. Allow to rise 1 hour, covered, in a warm draft-free area. Fry in Crisco oil at 350  until golden brown. Roll in sugar.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>Quick Caramel Rolls</Title>
<Subtitle>Topping:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>1/2 cup firmly packed brown sugar
1/2 cup margarine or butter, softened
2 TBSP light corn syrup</Ingredients>
<Subtitle>Rolls:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>3 to 3 1/2 cups flour
1/4 cup sugar
1 tsp salt
1 package active dry yeast
1 cup water
2 TBSP butter or margarine
1 egg</Ingredients>
<Subtitle>Filling:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>2 TBSP margarine or butter, softened
1/4 cup sugar
1 tsp cinnamon</Ingredients>
<Directions>Grease 9x13 inch pan. In small bowl, combine topping ingredients, blend well. Drop mixture by spoonfuls into prepared pan. Spread evenly. Set aside.
Lightly spoon flour into measuring cup, level off. In large bowl, blend 1 1/2 cups flour, sugar, salt and yeast. In small saucepan heat water and margarine until very warm (120-130 ). Add warm liquid and egg to flour mixture. Blend at low speed until moistened. Beat 3 minutes at medium speed. By hand, stir in 1 1/2 cups to 2 cups of flour until dough pulls cleanly away from sides of bowl. On floured surface, knead 1 minute. Press or roll dough into 15x7 inch rectangle.
For filling, spread 2 TBSP margarine over dough. Combine 1/4 cup sugar and cinnamon. Sprinkle over margarine. Roll up jelly roll fashion, starting with 15 inch side. Seal seams. Cut into 12 slices. Place cut side down in prepared pan. Cover loosely with plastic wrap and cloth towel. Let rise in warm place till light/doubled in size, about 35-45 minutes. Heat oven to 375 . Bake 25-30 minutes or until golden brown. Let cool 1 minute. Turn onto serving platter or aluminum foil. Makes 12 rolls. </Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>6-week Bran Muffins</Title>
<Ingredients>6 cups Kellogg’s All-Bran
2 cups boiling water
1 cup melted shortening or oil
3 cups sugar (or 2 sugar and 1 honey)
4 beaten eggs
1 quart buttermilk
5 cups flour
5 tsp baking soda
2 tsp salt</Ingredients>
<Directions>Pour boiling water over 2 cups of bran and let stand while assembling other ingredients. Mix the remaining bran with sugar, eggs, buttermilk and oil. Sift flour, soda and salt. Combine all ingredients and mix well. Bake in muffin cups as needed at 400  for 15-20 minutes. The batter may sit in refrigerator for 6 weeks – the longer the better. Raisins, dates or chopped apples may be added. Recipe can be cut in half.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>Stuffin’ Muffins</Title>
<Ingredients>1 loaf day-old bread – break apart into large pieces
1 raw medium onion, cut up
2 pieces celery, cut into small pieces
1 TBSP sage
2 sausages, raw – take off skin</Ingredients>
<Directions>Mix together. Place in muffin pans. Bake at 350  for 45 minutes. Then baste with turkey gravy or chicken broth. Bake another 15 minutes.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Bread/Muffins</Sectionhead>
<Title>Tuscany Pizza Dough</Title>
<Ingredients>Dissolve ¾ oz. fresh yeast in
¾ c. warm water
Add to 4 c. flour and 2 tsp. salt
Gently mix. Add 11/2 c. water and 
¼ c. olive oil. Mix well with hands.</Ingredients>
<Directions>Put flour on countertop, knead dough till smooth.
Place dough in large bowl. cover with a towel and place in a warm spot. Let rise about 2 hr. or till doubled in bulk. Punch down dough. Cut in half. Stretch by hands or with knuckles, turning constantly. Oil pan, then dough on pan, oil on top.
Add toppings. Bake in a 500 degree oven about 15 minutes.Zucchini Bread</Directions>
<Ingredients>3 eggs
1 cup oil
2 cups sugar (reduced)
1 TBSP vanilla
2 cups raw shredded zucchini
3 cups flour
1 tsp baking soda
1/4 tsp baking powder
1 tsp salt
1 TBSP cinnamon or pumpkin pie spice
1/2 cup chopped nuts</Ingredients>
<Directions>Put dry ingredients in one bowl. In a separate bowl beat eggs, add oil, vanilla and zucchini. Add to dry ingredients. Mix just until blended. Makes 2 loaves or l larger loaf. Bake at 350  for 1 hour. Freezes well.</Directions>
</Recipe>
</Section>

<Section>
<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Candy/Snacks</Sectionhead>
<Title>Anise Candy</Title>
<Ingredients>2 cups white sugar
2 cups lite karo syrup (1 pint)
red food coloring
1/2 tsp anise oil (buy at drug store)</Ingredients>
<Directions>Boil sugar and syrup very slowly till when dropped in cold water it can be broken between teeth without sticking (it will turn a light yellow color). Turn heat off - add red coloring as desired. Add anise oil and stir till both are blended. Pour into cold buttered 8x13 pan. While cooling cut into squares. It hardens from outside to the inside. Continue to groove into small (about 1 inch) squares till set. Cool completely. Break into squares and drop into bag with 1/4 cup sugar in it. Shake, then pour into candy jar.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Candy/Snacks</Sectionhead>
<Title>Baked Caramel Corn</Title>
<Ingredients>1 cup butter
2 cups brown sugar
1/2 cup karo syrup - clear
1 tsp salt
1/2 tsp baking soda
1 tsp vanilla
6 quarts popped corn</Ingredients>
<Directions>Keep corn hot in 250  oven. Melt butter, stir in brown sugar, syrup and salt. Bring to boil. Boil without stirring for 5 minutes. Remove from heat. Stir in soda and vanilla. Pour over popcorn and stir well. Bake in 250  oven for 1 hour. Stir every 15 minutes. Remove from oven.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Candy/Snacks</Sectionhead>
<Title>Caramels</Title>
<Ingredients>2 1/2 cups sugar
1 3/4 cups dark karo syrup
1 3/4 cups whipping cream -not whipped
1/2 cup butter
1 tsp vanilla
1/4 tsp salt
1 cup nuts - optional</Ingredients>
<Directions>Boil sugar, syrup and 1 cup whipping cream to 230  using a candy thermometer. Slowly add remaining cream so boiling doesn’t stop. Add butter. Boil to 240  and remove from stove. Add remaining ingredients. Spread in buttered jelly roll pan (10x15x1/2) and indent with a knife to individual size of caramels after it cools a little. When cool, cut with scissors and wrap in wax paper.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Candy/Snacks</Sectionhead>
<Title>Microwave Chocolate Fudge</Title>
<Ingredients>3 cups sugar
3/4 cup butter or margarine
2/3 cup evaporated milk (5 1/2 oz.)
1 12-oz. chocolate chips
1 7 1/2-oz. marshmallow creme
1 cup walnuts
1 tsp vanilla</Ingredients>
<Directions>Set microwave on high. In 2 1/2 quart casserole combine sugar, butter and milk. Heat 9-10 1/2 minutes or until sugar is dissolved - stirring twice. Add remaining ingredients and stir until chocolate is melted. Turn into well greased oblong baking dish. Chill.</Directions>
</Recipe>
</Section>

<Section>
<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Angel Cake Dessert</Title>
<Ingredients>Mix together 1 package of any flavor or Jell-O with 1 cup boiling water. Cool in refrigerator until partially set.
1 package vanilla instant pudding
1 cup milk
1 small can crushed pineapple with the juice
1 carton whipped cream, whipped</Ingredients>
<Directions>Break up 1 angel food cake
Mix all together and put into 9x13 pan. Refrigerate.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Apple Crisp</Title>
<Ingredients>1 cup flour
1 cup brown sugar
1/2-cup butter, cut into pieces
1 tsp. cinnamon</Ingredients>
<Directions>Mix together to form a crumbly mixture.
Peel and slice 7 or 8 cups Macintosh or any baking apples. Put the sliced apples in a baking dish and top with the crumb mixture. Bake at 375  for 30 minutes.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Aunt Leone’s Whipped Cream Frosting</Title>
<Ingredients>3/4 cup milk
2-3 TBSP flour
Whisk flour into milk. Cook on medium heat until thick. Cool.
Combine:
3/4 cup sugar
3/4 cup margarine</Ingredients>
<Directions>Beat until light in color and well blended.
Mix together the flour/milk mixture with the sugar mixture. Add 1 tsp vanilla. Beat until fluffy and looks like whipped cream, about 5 minutes.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Baked Custard</Title>
<Ingredients>2 large eggs
1/3 cup sugar
1/4 tsp salt
2 cups milk 
nutmeg for flavoring
1 tsp vanilla</Ingredients>
<Directions>Beat eggs, sugar and salt slightly to mix. Scald the milk and nutmeg flavoring (crinkly film forms on top) and pour into egg mixture. Add vanilla.
Strain into custard cups - 6 cups or 1 1/2 quart casserole dish. Sprinkle a little nutmeg over top. Bake at 350  for 30-35 minutes. Bake just until silver knife thrust into custard comes out clean. Immediately remove from heat. Serve cooled or chilled. </Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Berries-on-a-cloud</Title>
<Subtitle>Bottom:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>6 egg whites
1/2 tsp cream of tartar
1 1/2 cups sugar
1 tsp vinegar</Ingredients>
<Directions>Whip egg whites till foamy. Gradually add 1 1/2 cups sugar and beat until stiff. Add cream of tartar and vinegar. Mix well. Spread in 9x13 greased pan. Bake at 275  for 1 hour. Cool thoroughly.</Directions>
<Subtitle>Filling:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>8 oz. cream cheese
2 cups miniature marshmallows
1 pint whipping cream, whipped
1/2 cup sugar
1 tsp vanilla</Ingredients>
<Directions>Beat cream cheese, 1 cup sugar and vanilla. Fold in marshmallows and whipped cream. Spread over crust. Chill 8-12 hours. </Directions>
<Subtitle>Topping:</Subtitle><Directions>Top with 1 can cherry pie filling alone or mix 1 can drained frozen strawberries to the pie filling.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Blitz Kuchen</Title>
<Ingredients>1 cup sugar
1/2 cup butter
2 eggs
2 tsp baking powder
a pinch of salt
1 cup milk
2 cups flour</Ingredients>
<Directions>Mix the above ingredients together and pour into pan. </Directions>
<Subtitle>Topping:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>8 TBSP brown sugar
4 TBSP butter
2 TBSP flour
1/2 cup nuts
2 tsp cinnamon</Ingredients>
<Directions>Bake at 325  for 25 minutes.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Carrot Cake</Title>
<Ingredients>2 cups flour
2 cups sugar
1 tsp cinnamon
1 tsp salt
2 tsp baking powder
1 cup oil
4 eggs
3 cups shredded carrots </Ingredients>
<Directions>Beat all ingredients together-except carrots. Then fold in the shredded carrots. Bake at 350  for 35 minutes in a 9x13 pan. Cool.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Title>Frosting:</Title><Ingredients>1 stick margarine
8 oz. cream cheese
2 lbs. powdered sugar</Ingredients>
<Directions>Combine all ingredients till well blended. Frost cake. A few chopped nuts or some shredded carrots looks nice on top.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Title>Chocolate Sheet Cake</Title>
<Ingredients>1 cup water
2 TBSP cocoa
1/2 cup oil
1 stick (1/2 cup) butter
2 cups flour
2 cups sugar
1/2 tsp salt
1/4 tsp cinnamon (optional)
2 eggs
1/2 cup buttermilk
1 tsp baking soda
1 tsp vanilla extract</Ingredients>

<Subtitle>Icing:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>2 or 3 TBSP cocoa
1 stick (1/2 cup) butter
1 tsp vanilla
1/3 cup milk
2 1/2 cups powdered sugar
3/4 cups nuts
...continued</Ingredients>
<Directions>CAKE: In a saucepan, bring to boil the water, cocoa, oil and butter. In a large bowl, sift flour, sugar, salt and cinnamon. Pour the boiling liquid into the dry ingredients and mix. While mixing, add the eggs, buttermilk, baking soda and vanilla. Pour batter into a 12x18 inch cookie sheet. Bake at 350  for 20 minutes. 
ICING: In a microwave-safe bowl, combine cocoa, butter, vanilla and milk. Heat in microwave until mixture boils. Gradually add the powdered sugar and nuts and beat well. Spread the icing while the cake is hot.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Cranberry Cake With Brandy Sauce</Title>
<Subtitle>Mix together:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>2 cups flour
2 tsp baking powder
1 cup sugar
1/2 tsp salt</Ingredients>

<Subtitle>Add:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>1 cup milk
3 TBSP melted butter
2 cups cut-up cranberries
Bake 25-30 minutes at 350 </Ingredients>

<Subtitle>Sauce:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>1 cup cream
1/2 cup butter
1 cup sugar
Bring to boil, then add:
1 TBSP corn starch
1 double shot brandy OR 1 tsp vanilla
Pour sauce over warm or cooled cake.</Ingredients>

</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Fast Crust Custard Pie</Title>
<Ingredients>4 eggs
1/2 cup sugar
1/3 cup flour
1/8 tsp salt
2 cups milk
1 tsp vanilla</Ingredients>
<Directions>Beat the eggs and sugar together well. Mix together the flour, salt, milk and vanilla and then add to the egg/sugar mixture. Bake in a well-buttered 9 or 10 inch pie pan for 1 hour at 350 .
For coconut custard pie, add 1 cup coconut before pouring into the buttered pie pan.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Hawaiian Wedding Cake</Title>
<Ingredients>2 eggs, beaten
2 cups flour
2 cups sugar
1/2 cup to 1 cup nuts
20-oz. can crushed pineapple, including liquid
2 tsp baking soda</Ingredients>
<Directions>Combine ingredients in order written.
Bake in a 9x13 pan at 350  for about 40 minutes. Cool and then frost.</Directions>
<Subtitle>Frosting:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>4 TBSP margarine
8 oz. cream cheese
2 1/3 cups powdered sugar
1 tsp vanilla</Ingredients>
<Directions>Beat well. Spread over cake.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Hickory Nut Cake</Title>
<Ingredients>1 1/4 cup sugar
1/2 cup butter
2/3 cup sweet milk
1 3/4 cup bread flour
1/2 tsp salt
1 heaping tsp baking powder
1 tsp lemon flavoring
1 tsp vanilla
1 cup hickory nuts (cut)
5 egg whites (beaten and added last)</Ingredients>
<Directions>Cream butter and sugar. Add milk and flavorings. Add baking powder and salt to flour. Add dry ingredients, beating well. Fold in nuts and beaten egg whites. 1 large pan or 2 9” layers or 3 8” layers. Don’t over beat if mixer is used. After sugar, milk, butter emulsion is made with mixer finish by hand with wire whip. Bake at 350 .</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Lemon Angel Pie</Title>
<Subtitle>Pie Shell:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>3 egg whites
1/4 tsp cream of tartar
3/4 cup sugar</Ingredients>
<Directions>Preheat oven to 250  F. Butter 9” pie pan. Have the egg whites room temperature. Beat egg whites and cream of tartar in small bowl on high for 1 minute. Continuing on high speed, gradually add sugar, beating for five minutes or until the egg whites are stiff. Spread on bottom and sides of prepared pan. Bake 45 minutes. Cool</Directions>
<Subtitle>Pie Filling:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>4 egg yolks
1/2 cup sugar
3 TBSP lemon juice
1 cup whipping cream</Ingredients>
<Directions>Beat egg yolks in small bowl on high for 3 minutes. Gradually add sugar, beating on high speed for 2 minutes. Blend in lemon juice at low speed for 1 minute. Transfer to double boiler and cook 5 minutes or until thick, stirring constantly. Cool. Whip cream in small bowl on high speed for 2 minutes. Fold in the lemon custard on low speed for 1 minute. Fill pie shell and chill 12 hours or overnight. Serve with sweetened whipped cream garnish.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Lemon Bars</Title>
<Ingredients>1 cup flour
1/2 cup butter - Mom recommends only butter
1/4 cup powdered sugar</Ingredients>
<Directions>Mix like pie crust. Press into 9x13 pan. Bake at 350  for 15 minutes.
Add together:</Directions>
<Ingredients>2 cups sugar
1/4 cup flour
1 tsp baking powder
1/4 cup lemon juice
rind of 2 lemons
4 eggs</Ingredients>
<Directions>Mix together. Pour into crust. Bake an additional 25 minutes. Cool. Sprinkle with powdered sugar.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Libby’s Famous Pumpkin Pie Recipe</Title>
<Ingredients>2 eggs slightly beaten
1 16oz. can pumpkin
3/4 cup sugar
1/2 tsp salt
1 tsp cinnamon
1/2 tsp ground ginger
1/4 tsp ground cloves
1 13-oz. can evaporated milk</Ingredients>
<Directions>Preheat over to 425 . Combine filling ingredients in order given; divide evenly into pie shells. Bake 15 minutes. Reduce heat to 350  and continue baking an additional 45 minutes or until knife inserted in center of pie comes out clean.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Light Hickory Nut Cake</Title>
<Ingredients>1 1/2 cups sugar
1/2 cup butter
3 eggs
1 cup milk
2 cups cake flour
2 level tsp baking powder
1 cup finely chopped hickory nuts
1 tsp vanilla</Ingredients>
<Directions>Cream butter and sugar. Add one egg at a time and beat after each egg. Add milk and flour a little at a time and keep beating. Add chopped nuts mixed with two level TBSP of cake flour. Preheat oven to 350 . Place batter in flat loaf pan 14”x10”. Bake for 30 minutes. Cover with white icing. Cut in squares and place the meat of half a hickory nut on each square.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Lightened-up Chocolate Sheet Cake</Title>
<Ingredients>2 cups flour
1 1/2 cups sugar
1/4 tsp salt
1 tsp baking soda
1/4 tsp cinnamon (optional)
3/4 cup water
1/4 cup cocoa
6 TBSP butter
1/2 cup low-fat buttermilk
2 eggs
1 tsp vanilla
ICING: 1/4 cup cocoa
4 TBSP butter
1/3 cup non-fat milk
2 1/2 cups powdered sugar
1 1/2 tsp vanilla extract
1/4 cups nuts, toasted</Ingredients>
<Directions>To make the cake, preheat the oven to 375 . Spray a 10x15 inch jelly-roll pan with non-stick spray. Set aside. In a large bowl, combine the flour, sugar, salt, baking soda and cinnamon. In a small saucepan, place the water, cocoa, and butter. Over medium heat, bring to a boil, stirring often. Pour the boiling cocoa mixture over the flour mixture and stir to combine. Add the buttermilk, eggs and vanilla. Blend well. Pour into the prepared pan and bake for 18 to 20 minutes or until a toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean.
While the cake is baking, make the icing. Combine the cocoa, butter and non-fat milk in a small saucepan. When the cake is done, bring the icing ingredients to a boil, and then add the powdered sugar, vanilla and nuts. Blend well. Spread on the hot cake.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Old Fashioned Bread Pudding</Title>
<Ingredients>2 cups milk
4 cups coarse bread crumbs</Ingredients>
<Directions>Heat the milk until scalding and pour over the bread crumbs.  Let cool.</Directions>
<Subtitle>Add:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>1/4 cup butter, melted
1/2 cup sugar
2 eggs, slightly beaten
1/4 tsp salt
1/2 cup raisins
1 tsp cinnamon or nutmeg</Ingredients>
<Directions>Pour into buttered 1 1/2 quart casserole dish. Bake at 350  for 40-45 minutes, until knife comes out clean when put into pudding. Serve warm. Makes 6 servings. May add 1/2 cup cocoanut – plain or toasted.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Poke Cake</Title>
<Ingredients>1 package (2 layer size) white cake mix
1 3oz. package Jell-O gelatin, any flavor
1 cup boiling water
1/2 cup cold water</Ingredients>
<Directions>Prepare cake mix as directed on package, baking in a well-greased and floured 9x13 pan at 350  for 30-35 minutes. Cool in pan for 15 minutes, then poke with a fork at 1/2 inch intervals.
Dissolve the gelatin in boiling water. Add the cold water and spoon over cake in pan. Chill 3-4 hours. Top with cool whip. You can also make the cake in two layers and color each layer with a different flavor of gelatin for a party or Christmas.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Poppy Seed Torte</Title>
<Subtitle>Make the crust first:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>1 cup flour
1 stick margarine or butter
1/2 cup walnuts</Ingredients>
<Directions>Bake at 325  for 15 minutes. Watch closely so it doesn’t burn. Cool.
Beat 5 egg yolks and set aside. (save egg whites for later)</Directions>
<Ingredients>1 cup sugar (may reduce to 3/4 cup)
2 TBSP cornstarch
1 1/2 cup milk
1/4 cup poppy seed
1/4 cup salt</Ingredients>
<Directions>Cook in a saucepan till comes to a boil. Continue boiling till it thickens. Take off heat. Add egg yolk mixture slowly, stir. Mix 1 1/2 tsp gelatin with 1/4 cup cold water - stir into mixture. Add 1 tsp vanilla. Cool. 
In a separate bowl beat 5 egg whites well.</Directions>
<Subtitle>Add: </Subtitle>
<Ingredients>1/2 cup sugar
1/2 tsp cornstarch</Ingredients>
<Directions>Fold in cooked mixture. Pour into crust. Cool. 
Serve with whipped cream and nuts.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Pumpkin Cheesecake</Title>
<Ingredients>7 egg whites - beat until fluffy and set aside</Ingredients>
<Subtitle>Mix together:</Subtitle>
<Ingredients>1 1/2 cup ricotta cheese
2 egg yolks
2/3 cup sugar (reduced from 1 cup)
1 1/2 tsp vanilla
1 1/2 cup canned pumpkin - unsweetened
1 TBSP pumpkin spice
1 tsp baking powder</Ingredients>
<Directions>Add egg whites. Gently fold till blended. Pour into greased, floured tube pan. Bake at 350  for 50-60 minutes. Sprinkle with confectioners sugar over top when cool.</Directions>
</Recipe>

<Recipe>
<Sectionhead>Desserts</Sectionhead>
<Title>Raspberry Torte</Title>
<Ingredients>1 cup flour
1 stick margarine
1 cup pecans, crushed</Ingredients>
<Directions>Mix together like for pie crust.
Put in 9x13 pan and bake for 12 minutes in 350  oven. Cool.
Cream 8-oz. cream cheese, 3 TBSP milk and 1 cup powdered sugar. Fold in 6-oz. cool whip. Spread over cooled crust. Add a layer of fresh raspberries and cover with 6-oz. cool whip. Refrigerate.</Directions>
</Recipe>
</Section>
</Cookbook>
</Root>